尼古拉斯•凱奇
勞拉•德恩
《 我 心 狂 野 》
編劇、導演: 大衛•林奇
恐怖角
CAPE FEAR
南、北卡羅萊納州邊界的某處
SOMEWHERE ON THE BOROER
BETWEEN NORTH AND SOUTH CAROLINA
喂，賽勒，等等
Hey, Sailor, wait!
我有話對你說
I got something for you.
瑪麗葉塔告訴我
Marietta tells me you were trying to
- 你剛纔在廁所裡對她動手動腳 - 媽的
fuck her in the toilets. - Oh, man ...
你這個變態佬，連你馬子的老媽都想上
You crazy bad boy, trying to fuck your girl's mama!
你那小娘們對此會有何感想？
Tell me， how does that little cunt Lula feel about that?
知道嗎
You know ...
瑪麗葉塔剛給我這個，讓我宰了你
Marietta gave me this to kill you.
然後還答應把那小婊子給我
And then she said I'd be able to fuck Lula ...
(匹迪懲教所)
PEE DEE PENITENTIARY
(22個月零18天後)
22 MONTHS, 18 DAYS LATER
- 喂？   - 露拉在嗎？
Hello ...? - Is Lula there?
你是誰？
Who is this?
賽勒•瑞普利
Sailor Ripley.
我能跟露拉說話嗎？
Can I ... talk to Lula?
你休想
There's no way in hell!
- 你如果想見她，就是找死  - 什麼？
If you even think about seeing Lula, you're dead. - What?
我說得很明白，以後別再打電話來
You heard me. And don't you ever call here again!
媽媽
Mama?
你清楚剛纔是誰的電話
You know who that was.
你也清楚你不能見他
And you know you aren't,
我老實告訴你，從今往後
and I mean are not gonna see him ever.
不許你再見到他!
End of story!
去你的!
Like hell!
露拉
Lula!
- 賽勒!  - 我的小花生米
Sailor! - Peanut!
嗨，寶貝
Hey baby!
我給你準備了一個驚喜
I've got a surprise for you!
我的蛇皮夾克! 謝了，親愛的! 我有沒有告訴你
Hey, my snakeskin jacket! Thanks, baby! Did I ever tell you
這件夾克代表我對個人自由的信仰
that this jacket is a symbol of my
belief in personal freedom?
你講過9999次啦
About 50,000 times.
我在恐怖角訂了房，猜猜有什麼好事？
I got us a room at the Cape Fear. And guess what?
颶風酒吧裡來了瘋力樂隊
"Powermad" is at the "Hurricane"!
開車吧!
Stab it and steer!
老天，賽勒寶貝，你可真不簡單
Jeez Lou-eez, Sailor, you are something else ...
我15歲時，媽媽對我說我
When I was 15, my mama told me
很快我就會對性感興趣
that pretty soon I'd be starting to think about sex,
在我嘗試這種事之前，應該告訴她一聲
and that I should tell her before I did anything about it.
可我記得你說過你的"苟"叔叔
But I thought you told me your uncle Pooch
在你13歲那年強奸了你
raped you when you was 13?
是的
True.
"苟"叔叔不是我親叔叔
Uncle Pooch wasn't really an uncle.
他是我爸的生意伙伴
He was a business partner of my daddy's.
媽媽從來不知道我跟他的事
Mama never knew 'bout me and him ...
這是肯定的
that's for damn sure.
知道嗎？你是個蠢貨
You know what? You're a pumpkin.
天啊! 給我滾出去!
Oh, my God! Get out!
普奇叔叔3個月後死於車禍
Uncle Pooch died in a car crash 3 months later,
當時他在莫特爾海灘度假
on holiday in Myrtle Beach.
那地方車禍多得離奇
They still got way too much traffic there.
你有沒發現最近交通越來越擁擠？
Have you been noticin' the buildup in traffic?
又來了
Here she goes again.
對不起，賽勒
I'm sorry, Sailor,
可臭氧層正在慢慢消失
but that ozone layer is disappearin'.
總有一天早上，太陽升起來後
One of these mornings, the sun's gonna
就會像一束X光，把地球燒出個洞來
burn a hole clean through the earth like an electrical X-ray.
這種事是不會發生的，寶貝
That won't happen, honey.
起碼在咱們這輩子不會，要真到了那時
At least not in our lifetime.And by then,
大家會開著別克到月球去
they'll be driving Buicks to the moon.
你還好吧，親愛的？
You OK, honey?
那女人的笑聲讓我覺得好恐怖
That woman's laugh creeps me out.
我好像在哪聽過
Like something I've heard before.
像惡邪女巫在笑
Sounded like the Wicked Witch.
我倒覺得那隻是個開心的老太婆
Just sounded like an old gal having a good time to me.
準備好去跳舞了嗎？
You ready to go dancing?
我隨時都能去跳
I'm always ready to dance.
但要先親一個，一個就好
But I need my kiss first.Just one!
如果你不幫我阻止這件事，我就自己去請殺手
I'm gonna hire me a hit man, if you don't help me stop this thing.
我要打電話找馬切羅•桑托斯
I'm going to call Marcello Santos.
瑪麗葉塔，我會幫你的
Marietta, I am gonna help you.
所以別做得傻事
So don't get carried away.
你不會真的想讓桑托斯一伙插手吧？
You don't want to bring Santos and his bunch into this.
你嫉妒他，因為他對我餘情未了
You're just jealous of him 'cause he's still sweet on me.
你還和他見面？
You been seeing him again?
我的天!
Oh my God,
我真不敢相信!
I don't believe this!
強尼•費拉加特
Johnnie Farragut ...
你竟然信不過你的瑪麗葉塔？
who doesn't even trust his very own Marietta?
好吧，對不起，親愛的
Alright, I'm sorry honey, but ...
我太愛你了
I just love you,
纔會心生妒忌
and it just brings out ...
老天! 我恨自己這麼善妒
That ugly jealous side, I hate it, God!
別用舌頭，我塗了唇膏
No tongue! My lipstick.
親愛的，不要再為我擔心
Sweetheart, I want you to stop worrying about me,
還是考慮怎麼把露拉那個殺人犯手裡救出來
and start worryin' about how to get Lula from that murderer.
慢著，親愛的
Honey, wait a minute now;
賽勒不是殺人犯
Sailor ain't no murderer.
聽我說，不要老對他有成見
Now listen to me! You gotta get off that kick.
據我所知，賽勒在被牽涉進
As far as I know, Sailor was all clean before he got involved in
和露拉有關的那件事之前，是清白的
in that event with Lula.
而且他當時想保護她
And even there, he was trying to protect her.
李蒙那個瘋子是帶著刀子襲擊他們的
That crazy Bob Ray Lemon was comin' at them with a knife.
他很可能會殺了他們倆，你該感謝他纔對
He could've killed both of them.You ought to be thankin' him!
我不知道自己干嘛對你說這些
I don't know why I'm telling you this.
你當時在場，這件該死的事你親眼見到
You were there,you saw the whole damned thing!
難道不是嗎？
Didn't you?
賽勒小子!
Sailor boy!
你想不想
How'd you like
和露拉的媽媽玩玩？
to fuck Lula's mama?
不  伯母
No ... ma'am ...
- 我敢肯定不想  - 可露拉的媽媽想和你玩
I sure don't. - Lula's mama would like to fuck you.
弗琴太太，我想你非常需要杯咖啡醒醒酒
Mrs. Fortune, I really think you need a cup of coffee.
也許我當時是在場
Maybe I was there.
可我什麼也沒看到!
But I didn't see anything at all.
我隻知道那個敗類
All I know is,is that trash,
他空手活活打死了一個人
he killed a man with his bare hands,
那雙手很可能就在打我的壞主意
hands that are probably all over my baby right now!
親愛的，冷靜點
Oh, honey, settle down.
沒事了，別激動
It's all right, come on now.
沒事了
It's alright.
聽我說，我也希望露拉幸福
Now listen, I want what's best for her too.
我會盡我所能帶她回家，好嗎？
I'll do everything I can to bring her back home, OK?
寶貝，別折騰，我還有一個腳趾沒塗
Baby, quit bouncing.I got one more toe to do.
咱們去跳舞吧，小心肝
Let's go dancing, Peanut!
我已經整裝待發
I'm ready.
但我們最好小心點
But we better be careful.
媽媽肯定會叫強尼•費拉加特跟蹤我們
Mama's gonna have Johnnie Farragut after us.
他可是個有頭腦的偵探，知道多有頭腦嗎？
He's one clever detective.You know how clever?
- 怎麼個有頭腦法？- 他有一次告訴我.
How clever?- He told me once,
他能在華盛頓找到一個誠實的人
he could find an honest man in Washington.
再等兩分鐘，指甲油馬上就干
I just want two more moments,then my toes will be dry.
- 有件事我一直想不透，寶貝 - 什麼事？
One thing puzzles me, sugar.- What's that?
你己經20歲了
You're 20 years old.
難道沒想過為什麼你媽不讓我們在一起？
Ain't you ever curious as to why your mama wants to keep us apart ?
我告訴你好了，露拉
I'll tell you, Lula ...
不光是因為我殺了李蒙
it's more than me killing Bob Ray Lemon.
也許是我媽關心我有點過了頭
Maybe my mama cares for me just a little too much.
對，也許是
Yeah, maybe.
我隻是想給你一個告別之吻
I just want to kiss you goodbye.
因為你對露拉媽媽的底細知道太多
You know too much about Lula's Mama.
什麼意思？
What do you mean?
強尼告訴我，你曾經給桑托斯當過司機
Johnnie told me you were a driver for Marcello Santos.
- 那又怎麼樣？ - 說不定某天夜裡
So what? - So maybe one night,
你離火太近
you got too close to a fire.
所以你惹火上身，此外，你這狗屎
So maybe you're gonna burn.Besides, you're shit.
你以為我會讓我的寶貝女兒
You think I'd let my little girl
和你這種敗類在一起鬼混？
hang out with a piece of s-h-i-t like you?
臭小子，你還是老實待在糞坑裡
Kid, you belong in one of these toilets!
你這個惡心的白種母狗
You piece of white trash!
你
You ...
除非把我殺了，不然休想讓我離開露拉
You're gonna have to kill me to keep me away from Lula.
這事犯不著你操心，我會先把你那話兒切下來
Don't worry about that.First I'm gonna cut your balls off
再叫你自個兒咽下去
and feed them to you.
除非你把我殺了
You're gonna have to kill me.
放心，一切有我安排
I can arrange that.
我想這問題沒法很快解決
It's a problem I don't think is gonna go away too soon.
我準備違反保釋條例，帶你到加州享受燦爛陽光
I'm ready to break parole and take you out to sunny California!
- 賽勒!     - 你開心嗎？
Sailor!- You up for that?
就算起天涯海角，我也會跟著你
I'd go to the far end of the world for you, baby.
你知道我願意
You know that.
太棒了!
Rockin' good news!
指甲油干了嗎，甜心？
Are those toenails about dry yet,sweetheart?
咱們跳舞去
We've got some dancing to do!
你是想給我機會向女友證明愛意
You gonna give me the opportunity to prove my love to my girl?
還是像個紳士一樣給她道歉，免得自找麻煩？
Or you gonna save yourself some trouble and apologize to her?
別惹我，伙計
Don't fuck with me, man.
你身上那張魚鱗讓你看起來像小丑
You look like a clown in that stupid jacket.
這是蛇皮夾克
This is a snakeskin jacket..
它代表我的個性
It's a symbol of my individuality
和我對個人自由的信仰
and my belief in personal freedom.
王八蛋!
Asshole!
- 有種就來啊! - 賽勒，親愛的
Come here!- Sailor, honey ...
很抱歉在大家面前出你洋相
I'm sorry to do this to you here in front of a crowd and all...
但我要你站起來向我的女友道歉
But I want you to get up and apologize to my girl.
對不起
I'm sorry.
算了，你隻是找錯了對像
You just bumped against the wrong girl, that's all.
好了，買杯啤酒去去火
Get yourself a beer.
各位閱歌無數
You fellas have a lot of the same power "E" had.
想必也知道這首
Do you know this one?
小賽，你怎麼沒為我唱"柔情似水"？
Sail', how come you didn't sing me "Love me tender"?
你說過那是你最喜歡的情歌
You told me that was your favorite love song.
我也說過我隻為妻子唱這首歌
I told you I'd only sing "Love me tender" to my wife.
有沒有想像過
Did you ever think something ...
一陣風聲從你耳邊擦過
you can hear a wind ...
從奧茲國的惡邪女巫，飛到你跟前
and see the Wicked Witch of the East come flyin' in?
我在牢裡時，真的很想念你的古怪念頭
I really did miss your mind while I was out at Pee Dee.
當然也很想你的身體
The rest of your too, of course.
但你腦子裡的東西隻有上帝纔猜得透
But the way your head works is God's mystery.
你剛纔想到什麼？
What were you thinking?
其實，我在想抽煙的事
Well, I was thinking about smoking, actually.
我媽媽現在抽功勛牌
My mama smokes Merits now.
以前她抽總督牌
She used to smoke Viceroys.
從六年級我就開始偷她的煙
I started stealing 'em from her about 6th grade.
小賽，你什麼時候開始抽煙的？
When did you start smoking, Sail'?
大概是
I started when I was about ...
四歲那年
four.
我媽那時己經得肺癌死了
My mom was already dead then from lung cancer.
- 她抽什麼牌子？  - 萬寶路，和我一樣
What brand did she smoke?- Marlboros, same as me.
我猜我爸媽要不是因為抽煙死的
I guess both my mom and my daddy died
就是因為酗酒
of smoke or alcohol related illness.
- 老天，小賽，真對不起 - 不要緊，親愛的
Jeez, Sail', I'm sorry.- Its OK, honey.
反正我以前也很少和他們在一起
I hardly used to see them anyways.
我沒受多少家庭教育
I didn't have much parental guidance.
我的辯護人在聽證會上總是強調這點
The public defender kept saying that.
他是個好人，始終站在我這邊
He was a good boy, he stood by me.
我也站在你這邊，小賽
I'd stand by you, Sail',
不管有多艱苦
through anything.
哎呀，我親愛的
Hell, Peanut ...
我收拾了李蒙後，你就對我不離不棄
You stuck by me after I planted Bob Ray Lemon.
男人還能要求比這更多的東西嗎？
A man can't ask for more than that.
你令我感動，小賽
You move me, Sail'.
你真的令我感動
You really do.
你在我身體的最深處打下了烙印
You mark me the deepest.
對我來說，你就是我前世的孽緣
You're perfect for me too.
你讓我想起爸爸
You remind me of my daddy.
媽媽告訴我，他喜歡胸部堅挺
Mama told me he liked skinny women
身材瘦瘦的女人
with breasts that stood up and said "Hello".
他也有個長鼻子，和你一樣
He had a long nose too,just like yours.
我有告訴你我爸是怎麼死的嗎？
Did I ever tell you how my daddy died?
在我記憶裡，他是被燒死的
In a fire, as I recall.
是的
Yeah ...
媽告訴我，他把煤油潑在自己身上
Mama told me he poured kerosene all over himself,
點燃一根火柴
and lit a match.
那是在我認識你的前一年
That was the year before I met you.
不，我還沒找到他們
No, I haven't found them yet.
- 你放輕松點，好嗎？ - 強尼!
Just try to take it easy. - Johnnie!
在你找到露拉之前，我會一直守在電話旁
I'm going to stay right here, by this telephone,
等你一找到我就去接她
until you find Lula.And then I'm coming to get her.
所以，一到新奧爾良馬上給我打電話
So call me the second you get to New Orleans.
- 我會的  - 拜托，別再讓我失望了
I will, honey. - Please don't let me down again!
- 我會想你的 - 那就快去快回!- 好的，再見
I'll miss you. - Get going! - OK. Bye.
再見，親愛的
Bye, honey.
喂，我猜你現在已違反了假釋條例
Well, I guess you broke parole now.
現在？
You guess?
寶貝，那是在200哩前我們穿過波蒂縣時的事了
My parole was broke 200 miles back, when we burned Portagee County.
我想我會找個地方，寄張明信片給媽媽
I guess I'll send Mama a postcard from somewhere.
我不希望她為了我瞎著急
I don't want her to worry more than necessary.
那不是我找你來的原因，桑托斯
That's not why I called you here, Santos.
聞起來不像是酷牌的
That don't smell like a Kool.
不是，它是人生課程的一部分
It ain't. It's part of the lessons of life.
開門見山吧
Just tell me what you want.
你難道沒有開始擔心什麼對你是有害的？
You ain't gonna start worrying about what's bad for you?
我是說  你現在可是和貨真價實的殺人犯一起穿州過界
I mean, here you are, crossing state lines with a real murderer ...
是過失殺人犯，親愛的，不是殺人犯，別誇大其辭
A man slaughterer, honey, not murderer. Don't exaggerate.
好吧，就算是過失殺人犯
OK, man slaughterer ...
此人剛剛違反假釋條例，而且滿肚子壞水
who just broke parole and has only immoral purposes in mind,
- 但隻對你這位美麗小姐 - 上帝保佑
as far as you're concerned. - Thank the Lord!
其實你沒有讓我失望，小賽
Well, you ain't let me down yet.. Sail'.
你比世上其他人強多了
That's more than I can say for the rest of the world.
你真體貼，心肝
You please me too, Peanut
你要我用槍打爆賽勒的腦袋？
You want me to shoot Sailor in the brains, with a gun.
是的
Yes.
- 從前額？- 正是
In the forehead?- Yes.
不對
Wrong!
從後腦勺打進去更爽
It's always better to blow a hole through the back of the head.
正好從裡面穿過
Right through ...
鼻梁骨
to the nose.
當場就能叫他命喪黃泉，神仙都救不回
Lots of irreparable damage.
明白了？
See?
我早料到你辦事穩妥
I knew you had it under control.
你反應有點慢，但己開始進入狀況了
You are a little slow, but you're beginning to get it.
你怎麼不讓強尼•費拉加特去？
Why didn't you send Johnnie Farragut?
或許我已經叫了呢
Maybe I did.
你不妨到新奧爾良打聽一下
Why don't you look in New Orleans?
- 露拉總是把這名字掛在嘴邊 - 有個條件
Lula always talks about that town. - On one condition;
你得讓我干掉強尼•費拉加特
You give me permission to kill Johnnie Farragut.
桑托斯，拜托!
Santos, please!
你該不會想說，還對他情深意重吧？
You're not telling me you're that sweet on him?
- 什麼？沒有    - 你對他真這麼痴心？
What? No ... - Are you that sweet on him?
- 不是，可    - 遲早他會發現
No, but ... - One day he's gonna find out
我們和阮迪先生干的勾當，到時麻煩就大了
what we're up to with Mr. Reindeer,and he can cause us a lot of trouble.
沉默等於默許
I'll take your silence as a "yes".
- 不，不行，桑托斯   - 噓，別著急
No, ... no, Santos ... - Shhh, it's OK.
- 沒事的     - 不，別殺強尼
It's alright.- No! You're not gonna kill him!
- 你不能殺他   - 不會的，不會
You're not gonna kill him! - No, no ...
不，別殺強尼，你要殺的是賽勒
No, not Johnnie.You kill Sailor!
我是打算要殺死賽勒
I am going to kill Sailor.
你放心好了
You can be certain of that.
喂，阮迪先生，我是桑托斯
Hello, Mr. Reindeer. Marcello Santos speaking.
嗨，是您啊，桑托斯先生!
Mr. Marcello Santos. Hey there!
您上個月給我的貨真不賴
That was great shit you sent last in last month.
我有一件麻煩事
I've got a problem.
事實上，是兩件
A couple of problems, in fact.
兩件麻煩事？
A couple of problems?
每一件你都得往我的郵箱裡投一枚銀幣
For each problem, drop a silver dollar through my mail slot.
再附上所有的詳細資料
With all particulars.
我們會替你打理好的
We'll work out "il conto" later.
祝你愉快!
Have a beautiful day!
就像我們
We are.
注意行為檢點，這是傳道家吉米的地盤
Keep them panties up,we're in Jimmy Swaggart country!
知道嗎？
You know what?
蘇西那小賤人偷了我的梳子
That little bitch Susie stole my comb.
我最恨這種事
I hate that.
那個小騷貨
The stupid little shit!
我在打電話
Phone's ringing.
唐娜
Juana.
今天有人給我送來兩個銀幣
A couple of silver dollars came my way today.
其中一個是你的，還有一份受益人的資料
I'm sending one to you, with a paper on the beneficiary.
老規矩，隻要能完成任務
As usual, you are completely free to fulfill the obligation
你想用什麼方式都可以
in any manner you so desire.
叫雷吉和無影來這裡
In fact, send Reggie and Drop Shadow over,
取銀幣和資料
for the silver dollar and the papers.
馬上
Now.
他們已經上路了，另外那枚給了誰？
They're on their way. Who's getting' the second silver dollar?
這個你不用操心
That's for me to know.
成交？
Yeah?
多謝了，阮先生
Thanks, Mr. Reindeer.
玩個痛快，親愛的
Have fun, darling.
你好啊，我的小伙子
How you doin', my boy?
有時候，當我們在做愛時
Sometimes, when we're making love,
你幾乎要把我帶到彩虹上，讓我飄飄欲仙
you just about take me right over that rainbow.
你對我了解得一清二楚，知道我想要什麼
You're so aware of what goes on in me,I mean, you pay attention.
我發誓，寶貝，你那根是最棒的
And I swear, baby, you got the sweetest cock.
你在我裡面時，它好像在對我說話
It's like it's talking to me when you're inside.
你和我真是天生一對
You get right on me.
我沒法不承認，你是個危險的小芭比
You are dangerously cute, baby, I got to admit it.
咱們去見識一下新奧爾良的聲色犬馬
Let's go out into the crazy world of New Orleans!
再來一份油炸95蕉三明治
Let's get a fried banana sandwich.
這簡直是我見過最有趣的小玩意兒
That's about the cutest thing I've ever seen.
笨人就像瘟疫，把地方搞得亂糟糟，你們都瞧見啦
Pigeons spread diseases and mess up the place. You've seen it.
偉大古老的新奧爾良!
The big N.O.!
桑托斯？我不知道
Santos? I don't know ...
我改變主意了
I'm having second thoughts.
你想怎麼樣？
Guess what?
覆水難收，難道你不知道？
There's no turnin' back, remember?
- 我現在隻想大開殺戒 - 桑托斯
I'm in a killing mood. - Santos!
- 我在波本街上看見你的男朋友 - 我拿不定主意
I saw your boyfriend on Bourbon Street. - I'm not sure ...
什麼？你現在在新奧爾良？
What? Are you in New Orleans?
瘋婊子
Crazy fucking bitch!
姑娘們!
Ladies!
你們是什麼？
What are you?
你們不僅僅是一張帶著該死的微笑的臉
You're not just a pretty face with a fucking smile.
你們在這兒是為了讓阮先生快活的
You're here to make Mr. Reindeer happy.
讓他享受段美好時光
And to show him a good time.
別自討苦喫
Do not bring misfortune upon yourselves.
把銀幣給你時忘了
When I gave you the silver dollar, I forgot
忘了把這信封一起給你
to include the contents of this envelope.
現在把它送給你
They are to be returned.
下手前，先把它亮出來
Show it just before the deed.
我知道那天我學到人生重要一課
I knew I had an important lesson to learn that day.
當她走到最高一級時，我把手插進她兩腿間
When she got to the top step,I stuck my hand between her legs.
寶貝，你可真是個壞小子!
Baby, what a bad boy you are!
她也這麼說
That's just what she said.
我的老二硬得像石頭一樣
I had a boner with a capital "O".
總之，我發現她的房間
Anyway, I found her lying
塞滿槍支和色情雜志
in a room filled with guns and porno magazines.
於是我又把手插進她兩根大腿
So, I slid my hand between her legs again,
她緊接著就把腿合了起來
and she closed her thighs.
你撩得我受不了了，甜心
You're exciting me, honey.
接著呢？
Then what did she do?
她把臉半埋在枕頭裡
Her face was half pushed into the pillow,
我記得她轉頭看看我，說道:
and I remember, she looked back over her shoulder at me and said;
我不給你吹喇叭，別讓我給你吹
"I won't suck you. Don't ask me to suck you."
多可惜，她不知道自己錯過了最好的
Poor baby, she doesn't know what she missed.
- 她頭發什麼顏色？ - 很深的黑色
What color hair did she have? - Jet black,
但男士們都比較喜歡金發女郎
but gentlemen prefer blondes.
總之，聽聽這段
Anyway, dig this;
她轉過身子
She turns over,
褪掉她那條橘色內褲
peels off them orange pants,
兩條腿分得很開
spreads her legs real wide
然後對我說: 咬一口桃子吧
and says to me; "Take a bite of peach."
我的天! 親愛的，看來你是賺了
Jesus, honey, you more than sort of got what you come for.
寶貝，你最好趕快帶我回旅館
Baby, you better run me back to the hotel.
你撩得我全身比柏油還要熱
You've got me hotter than Georgia asphalt.
不說了，但放過我吧，心肝
Say no more, but go easy on me, sweetheart,
明天還得開很久的車
tomorrow we got a lot of driving to do.
比柏油還熱
Hotter than Georgia asphalt.
我們要是一輩子相親相愛，豈不棒透了？
Wouldn't it be fabulous if we someway stayed in love forever?
有時你冒出的念頭真夠絕頂古怪
You think of the weirdest damn things to say sometimes, Peanut.
我們不是一直都很快活嗎？
Ain't we been doing a pretty fair job thus far?
你很清楚我指的是什麼，甜心
Oh, you know exactly what I mean, sugar.
這會讓未來變得簡單又美好
It'd make the future so simple and nice.
我這輩子做過一些
I've done a few things
我不怎麼引以為傲的事
in my life which I ain't too proud of.
但從現在起，我不會做任何虧心事
But from now on I ain't gonna do nothin' for no good reason.
我還真知道
All I know for sure is there's more than a few bad ideas
我們周圍的確有不少壞念頭
runnin' loose out there.
有件事我從來沒對你提起過
There's something I ain't never told you about.
這個故事提醒人們要對壞念頭吸取教訓
This here's a story with a lesson about bad ideas.
什麼故事？
What's that?
我的表兄戴爾一天到晚都受壞念頭折磨
Well, my cousin Dell was always fighting bad ideas.
他非常喜歡聖誕節，我們常常叫他
See, Dell loved Christmas.We used to call him
"聖誕仔"
"Jingle Dell".
他希望一年到頭都是聖誕
He wanted Christmas to last all year long.
如果他媽媽告訴他，現在纔是夏天
He sure would scream when his mom told him it was summer,
聖誕節還要等上六個月，他就會尖聲怪叫
and Christmas was six months off.
他還說
Also, he said ...
總覺得有一群戴著黑橡皮手套的人
he felt there's men
跟著他四圍走
with black rubber gloves who were following him around.
戴爾說他對聖誕節的鐘愛
Dell said that trust in the spirit of Christmas was destroyed
被戴黑手套的外星人給破壞了
by ideas being controlled by aliens wearing black gloves.
他們會逼他做各種事
These aliens would get Dell to do all kinds of things.
然後他話題一轉，談起天氣
Then he'd carry on about the weather,
說起外星人是如何控制地球的天氣
talk about how rainfall is controlled by aliens on earth.
露提阿姨告訴他，有一天他會發現
Aunt Rootie told him that one day he would realize
戴黑手套的外星人其實就是他自己
that the alien wearing the black gloves was him,
不是別人
and him alone.
聽起來老戴爾的問題不小
Sounds like old Dell was more than just a bit confused.
戴爾真是活受罪
Dell was learning a hard lesson.
居然整晚不睡，拼命做三明治
It got so he would stay up all night making sandwiches.
戴爾，你在做什麼？
Dell, what are you doing?
我在做我的午飯!
I'm making my lunch!
媽媽告訴我，戴爾的媽媽露提阿姨
Mama told me Aunt Rootie, that's Dell's mama,
在他的內褲上找到蟑螂
found cockroaches in Dell's underwear.
有一回，她還發現戴爾
One time, she found Dell
把一隻大蟑螂放到屁眼上
putting one big cockroach on his anus.
老天! 乖乖
Hell, Peanut!
這可不怎麼好玩
It ain't so funny now, though.
戴爾失蹤了
Dell disappeared.
從此沒人見過他
Nobody's seen him since.
可惜他沒辦法
Too bad he couldn't visit
拜訪那位奧茲國的魔法師
that old Wizard of Dz,
從他那裡得到一些好建議
and get some good advice.
可惜我們都不能，寶貝
Too bad we all can't, baby.
是你嗎，強尼？
Are you there, Johnnie?
怎麼了，親愛的？
What's wrong, honey?
強尼，親愛的，我有事告訴你
Johnnie, sweetheart. Wait, I've got something to tell you.
我想讓你知道
I want you to know something.
我做了件蠢事，很蠢
I've done something so bad, real bad.
- 什麼事？  - 電話裡說不清楚
What?   - Not on the phone! No ...
我明天到新奧爾良，當面告訴你，行嗎？
I'm coming to New Orleans tomorrow to tell you in person. OK?
別這樣對我，換了我，你也會急的，快說吧
Don't do this to me. You'd freak out if I did that to you. Now what is it?
不，我不會在電話裡說
No,I'm not gonna tell you on the phone.
但是親愛的，我馬上就要動身去跟他們
But honey, I gotta leave right now and get on their trail.
他們來過這裡，今天早上從巴西旅館走了
The kids were here. They checked out of the Hotel Brazil this morning.
不!
No!
留在原地別動! 哪兒都別去
Stay right there! Don't go anywhere!
我搭七點的飛機，明天就到皮德蒙特
I'm coming in on Piedmont tomorrow, on the 7 o'clock flight.
- 我們一起去追露拉   - 好，如果你一定要這麼做
We're going after Lula together! - OK, if that's what you want.
但是我反對
But I'm against it!
明天
7 o'clock,
晚上七點，親愛的
tomorrow evening. Sugar, ...
然後到我們最喜歡的法國餐館喫晚飯，好嗎？
We'll have dinner at our favorite French restaurant, OK?
你安排一下，好嗎？到時見
You fix it up. OK, bye now?
我愛你
I love you.
瑪麗葉塔？
Marietta?
咱們還剩多少錢，寶貝？
How much we got left, baby?
不到一百塊
Under 100.
要不要你休息一下
You want me to drive
- 讓我開一會兒？ - 好主意
so you can get a bit of rest? - Yeah, that'd be good.
德州聖安東尼奧電臺，今晚你都在想些什麼？
Come in, San Antonio, Texas. What's on your mind this evening?
我剛動了一個心髒手術
I just had triple bypass,open-heart surgery,
但聽你這種人的節目讓我恨不得馬上出院
and it's people like you who make me wanna get out of the hospital ...
怎麼會有這種垃圾？
How can anyone listen to this crap?
她不久前離婚，槍殺自己三個小孩，一個七歲
... for her recent divorce, shot her three children, aged seven ...
一位法官
A judge
偏袒被告約翰•洛伊
praised defendant John Roy, but was dismayed to learn
但在聽說洛伊有奸尸的行為後驚慌失措
that he'd had sex with the corpse.
什麼？
What?
去年十月，印度當局把500隻海龜放進恆河
State authorities, last October released 500 turtles into the Ganges,
企圖改善河水的污染狀況
to try and reduce human pollution,
現在準備將鱷魚放進河裡，以吞喫窮人的尸體
and will now use crocodiles to eat corpses dumped by poor Hindus ...
我的天! 這簡直就像《活死人之夜》
Holy shit! It's Night of the Living Dead!
- 怎麼了，寶貝？     - 我再也受不了這個收音機
What's that, Peanut? - I can't take any more of this radio!
我這輩子還沒聽過這麼多恐怖的事
I've never heard so much shit in all my life!
賽勒•瑞普利，馬上給我換個音樂臺! 快
Sailor Ripley, you get me some music now! I mean it!
性攻擊的受害者  分尸  強暴
... victim of a sexual assault ... ... mutilated ... raped ...
強尼，現在我不能告訴你，但是聽我說
Johnnie, I can't tell you now, honey, but listen;
我們能否今晚就出發？
Is there any way, any way that we could get on the road tonight?
昨晚你打電話給我時一定是受了很大刺激
Something was upsetting you bad last night when you called.
你肯定想告訴我什麼事
And you wanted to tell me.
所以我推測你需要我的幫助
So I figured that you wanted me to help you.
的確是
I did.
你說得沒錯，但那是昨晚的事
Oh, I did.But that was last night.
現在我需要你幫忙，我們要找到露拉，否則就遲了
Now I need your help. We have to find Lula before it's too late.
- 親愛的，有件事我想問你  - 說吧
Honey, I have to ask you something. - Okay.
桑托斯也參與了這件事嗎？
Is Santos involved in this in any way?
當然沒有
Hell no!
你以為我會不跟你商量 就做出這種事嗎？
Do you think I would do something like that without coming to you?
親愛的，對不起
I'm sorry, honey.
- 都是普謙斯基那狗雜種惹的禍! - 誰，"苟"叔叔？
Goddamned Pucinski, son of a bitch! - Who, Uncle Pooch?
那個把桑托斯介紹給你和克萊德的王八蛋
The son of a bitch who introduced Santos to you and Clyde.
強尼
Johnnie ...
以前的事別提了
That's all the past.
現在你和我必須做的是
Now what you and I have to do ...
是考慮咱們的未來
is think about our future.
這話當真？
Do you mean that?
當然是，敢不敢用你的性感臀部打賭？
You bet your sweet ass I do!
天哪
Gosh.
我說過再見到你真太好了嗎？
Did I tell you how great it was to see you again?
纔說了五遍而已
Just about five times, that's all.
- 天，強尼，我愛你! - 我也愛你
Oh God, Johnnie, I love you! - I love you too.
我們趕快離開這裡去找露拉吧
Let's get our backsides out of this town and go get my Lula!
什麼事讓你心煩了，親愛的？
What's troublin' you, sugar?
露拉，你知道
You know, Lula ...
我從來沒告訴過你，遇見你之前我是做什麼的
I never told you what all I was doing before I met you.
我以為你是個到處混的酷哥
I just figured you were out being Mr. Cool.
不全是
Not exactly, sugar.
我們如今的麻煩也與我當年的工作有關
One reason we're in this trouble is because of what I was doing.
我曾經想要告訴你
I tried to tell you this before.
你嚇到我了，寶貝
You're scaring me, baby.
凡事都有好壞兩面
Well, there's a good side as well as a bad side to it.
如今好的一面是我認識你爸爸克萊德，他是個好人
The good side is that I knew your daddy. Clyde was a good guy.
- 你認識他？ - 是的
You knew my daddy? - Yes.
我認識他
I sure did.
壞的一面是
The bad side of it ...
我曾經給一個叫馬切羅•桑托斯的人開過車
is I did some driving for a man named Marcello Santos.
真該死
Oh Shit.
我後來辭了工
I quit working for him,
但在那之前，我有天晚上到了一所房子
but just before I did,I ended up one night at a house.
我當時並不知道
I didn't know it then,
那就是你家
but it was your house.
我不知道他們以為那晚我看到了什麼
I don't know what they think I saw that night.
我隻是待在車裡，直到整間房子燒了起來
I was just sitting out in the car,'til the whole place went up in flames.
天啊，賽勒，我爸爸就在那天晚上死的
Oh God, Sailor,that's the night my daddy died!
我知道，親愛的
I know, sugar.
老爸？
Daddy?
那是
That's ...
你藏著的大秘密，小賽
some big secret you've been carrying, Sail'.
我們都藏有不可告人的秘密，寶貝
We all got a secret side, baby.
但願你別以為我還向你撒了別的謊
I hope you don't think I been lyin' to you about other things.
露拉，你在聽嗎？
Lula, you there?
對，我在聽
Yeah, I'm here ...
你在生我的氣？
You upset with me?
隻是感到很震驚
It just shocking sometimes ...
聽到事情原來並非和你想的那樣
when things aren't what you thought they were.
但我們已經沒法回頭，不是嗎？
We're really in the middle of it now, ain't we?
我很快就收拾好，你在樓下等我
I'm gonna pack real fast, then I'll meet you downstairs.
我的天，要是今晚能和你一起享用那張大床就好了
My God, what we could've done on that kingsize bed tonight!
- 別擔心，我會給你補償的   - 那好
Don't worry, I'll make up for it! - Alright.
- 待會見 - 好的
See you in a minute. - Okay.
瑪麗葉塔
Marietta ...
那是什麼東西？
What's that?
不知道，像衣服
I don't know ... Looks like clothes.
天啊，賽勒!
Oh God, Sailor!
一樁嚴重的車禍
One bad car accident.
我們該怎麼辦？
What should we do?
不知道，但是得幫幫那個女孩，帶她去鎮上
I don't know, but we got to help that girl, get her to a town,
但願別讓人發現我違反假釋規定
and hope nobody finds out that I broke parole.
發卡
This bobby pin ...
我找不到了
I can't find it.
媽媽會宰了我的  我的信用卡都在裡面
My mother's gonna kill me ... ... it's got all my cards ...
都在錢包裡
It was in my pocket.
錢包不見了，幫我找找
Now my pocket's gone.Gotta help me find it ...
我所有的信用卡  都在錢包裡
All my cards ...and it was in my pocket, and ...
我的錢包不見了! 她開始罵我了
My purse is gone!Now she tells me!
- 我們快抓住她!- 她能活下來嗎？
Let's get a hold of her!- Is she going to make it?
不知道，但她的血會流我們一車
Don't know, but she's gonna bleed all over our car!
嘿  嘿，姑娘
Hey ... hello! Girl!
跟我們走，親愛的
Come with us, honey!
別踫我
Leave me alone!
羅伯特？
Robert?
羅伯特!
Robert!
媽的
Shit.
我頭發裡有該死的粘乎乎的東西
Got this damned sticky stuff in my hair ...
我頭發裡有粘乎乎的東西
... got sticky stuff in my hair.
最好跟我們走，親愛的，來吧
Better come with us, honey. Come on!
我要找錢包  別告訴我媽媽，求求你們
Gotta find my wallet ... Don't tell my mother, please.
天啊，她會宰了我的
God, she's gonna kill me!
不用擔心這個
Can't worry about that ...
- 我的梳子在哪？   - 天啊，她會在我們面前死掉
Where's my hairbrush? - God, she's dying right in front of us.
幫我拿一下唇膏
Get my lipstick ...
在我的錢包裡
It's in my purse.
她死在我們面前，賽勒
She died right in front of us, Sailor ...
為什麼她非要這麼做？
Why'd she have to go and do that?
我們走吧，心肝
Let's get outta here, honey.
上天保佑
Jesus, Mary and Joseph!
我真是一點兒都想不通
I don't understand this one tiny bit.
說好我在樓下大廳等他
See, he told me to wait for him here in that lobby there.
可現在我感覺他發生了什麼可怕的事
What I feel is that something terrible has happened to him.
也許我們應該報警？
Perhaps we should call a local law enforcement officer?
不，千萬不要，請別這麼做
No, please! Please no!
我最不願意看到警察插手
The last thing I need is some damned policeman
在這裡問東問西
moving and going around here ...
不行，我不能容忍  不能
No, I just can't ... no ... no.
對不起，我剛纔肯定是忘了這個
I am sorry ... I must have overlooked this.
真的很抱歉，夫人
I'm truly
'
sorry, ma am.
是什麼？
What?
可不可以  ？
Could you ...?
"約了朋友釣魚
"Gone fishing with a friend ...
或者還去獵野牛"
and maybe buffalo hunting, too."
獵野牛？
Buffalo hunting?
"我去獵野牛"？
"I've gone buffalo hunting."?
該死的，"獵野牛"是什麼意思？
What the fuck does "Buffalo hunting" mean?
我肯定我不會明白，我是說
Well, I am sure I wouldn't know, I mean ...
我的天
My God ...
他害怕了
He's afraid.
他又臨陣脫逃!
He's done it again!
這個王八蛋又當逃兵!
The fucker split!
"我做了一個承諾"
"I've made a commitment."
瑪麗葉塔!
Marietta!
桑托斯!
Santos!
趁這個機會，我懇請你們
Gentlemen, I'd like to take this opportunity to ask you;
- 滾出去!  - 這麼無禮
Please, clear out! - How rude!
- 我也要？  - 對，你也滾
Me too? - Yeah, you too.
你對強尼做了什麼？他在哪？
What did you do to Johnnie? Where's Johnnie?
這兒發生了什麼事？
What's happening here?
告訴我發生了什麼事，桑托斯，告訴我
Tell me what's happening here! Santos, tell me!
你哭了？
You been crying?
你得改掉哭鼻子的壞習慣，明白嗎？
You gotta cut out this crybaby stuff, you know?
你現在是我的女人，桑托斯
You're my girl now, and Santos ...
桑托斯
Santos ...
桑托斯要擦掉這些淚珠
Santos wants to wipe away the tears,
讓你快樂
and make you happy.
你得告訴我
I want you to tell me ...
你對強尼做了什麼事？有沒有傷害他，快說
Did you do anything to Johnnie?Did you hurt him? I want to know.
我沒有對強尼•費拉加特做任何事
I did not do anything to Johnnie Farragut.
你能以你母親的名義發誓？
You swear, on your mother?
- 我發誓，以我母親的名義 - 天啊! 天啊
I swear. On my mother. - God! Oh God!
來吧，我們得走了
Come on. We have to go.
我得到消息:
I got word;
那兩個孩子正在穿越德州
The kids are moving through Texas.
大團圓結局正在安排，很快就會在那上演
And I think a happy end is being arranged there.
這就對了，笑一個
That's it, give me a smile!
桑托斯
Oh Santos.
你是唯一一個
You're the only one
總是為我兩肋插刀的人
that always came through for me.
我知道你現在怕得要命，強尼,再來一個吻，雷吉
I smell your shit now, Johnnie. Give us one more kiss, Reggie!
噢，操我!
Oh, fuck me!
操我!
Fuck me!
我們現在要獵野牛了
We hunt buffalo now.
等不及了!
Can't wait no more!
記住，數到十
Remember the number ... ten!
我沒法攔住她，強尼
I can't stop her, Johnnie.
但我會拿著這把老槍站在你身後
But I gonna be standing behind you with this big old gun!
一把海軍陸戰隊用的老家伙!
It's a Marine issue!
開始了
I go out now ...
- 雷吉!  - 有
Reggie!  - Yes?
給他看看!
Show him now!
親愛的
Honey ...
差點忘了讓你瞧瞧!
I forget to show you this!
桑托斯？
Santos?
天啊，瑪麗葉塔，我親愛的
Oh God, Marietta, honey ...
One ...
- 再會了  - 2
Bye now!  - two ...
3  4
three ... four ...
我焚身以火，雷吉!
Gettin' too hot now, Reggie!
five ...
感覺自己
... feeling myself ...
six ...
seven ...
eight ...
nine ...
操我，雷吉!
Fuck me now, Reggie!
10!
ten!
(德州金槍魚鎮)
到底為什麼你要到金槍魚鎮來，小賽？
Why in the hell d'you want to come to Big Tuna, Sail'?
我知道，這裡不是翡翠城
I know it's not exactly Emerald City ...
雖然這離加州也太遠了
Not as bad as the weather, ...
但還不至於比這天氣更糟
'though it's a long way off that road to California.
到底為什麼你要到這兒來，寶貝？
Why in the hell d'you want to come here, baby?
啊，瞧這兒!
Oh, look at this!
你想要什麼，蛇皮先生？
What do you want, Mr. Snakeskin?
我來是想知道你會不會告訴我，是否有人想殺我
I was hoping you could tell me if there's a contract out on me.
- 我真的需要知道  - 誰想殺你？
I really need to know.  - By who?
桑托斯，或是瑪麗葉塔•佛曲
Santos. Or Marietta Fortune.
聽說你和那婊子的閨女打得火熱
I heard you were going with that bitch's daughter.
- 沒錯               - 你是天字第一號蠢蛋
You heard right.  - You are one big, stupid asshole.
難道你不知道她媽和桑托斯合謀殺了她爸？
Don't you know that her mami and Santos killed her daddy?
也許有天晚上，你離火太近
So maybe one night you got too close to a fire ...
因此引火自焚
So maybe you're gonna burn.
- 我什麼都沒看到.  - 當然，可我看到了
I didn't see nothin'. - Sure. I did.
桑托斯!
Santos!
是不是他們有密謀？
Is there a contract?
咱們有過約定: 彼此互相提供消息
We had a deal once; We'd tip each other off if we heard.
我知道，我還記得
I know. I remember.
那麼？
Well?
我沒收到任何風聲
I heard of nothing.
謝了
Thanks.
小賽，親愛的，是你嗎？
Sail', honey, is that you?
正是我!
The one and only!
- 拿到機油了嗎，親愛的？  - 是的，先生!
D'you get that oil, baby? - Yes siree!
我遇到一個叫賴的家伙，他開修車檔
I met a guy called Red. He owns a garage.
什麼味道？
What's that smell?
我吐了
I barfed.
我原來想去廁所吐，結果卻撞錯門
I tried to make it to the bathroom, but it was the wrong door.
可能是長途跋涉讓我作嘔，親愛的
I think all this driving is upsetting me, baby.
你覺得我們能在這兒待上幾天，休息一下嗎？
D'you think we could stay here and rest a couple of days?
你暈車，對不對？
Are you carsick, sweetheart?
我猜是有點
A little, I guess.
賽勒，親愛的:
Oh Sailor, honey;
我希望那個女孩的死不會叫我們倒霉運
I hope seeing that girl die didn't jinx us.
我給你買了這個
I got this for you.
它有40種不同的味道
It has 40 different flavors.
每一種都代表我愛你的一個理由
One for about every reason I love you.
小賽，我會好好珍藏
Sail', I'm gonna save this.
即使我喫它
But if I ever eat it,
喫的時候我也會記著你
I'll be thinking of you.
"一輛汽車在118號公路發生車禍，司機羅伯特•布蘭登
"Robert Brenton and two passengers, William Reese
及車上兩名乘客，威廉•瑞斯和茱莉•戴全部喪生"
and Julie Day, were killed when his car crashed on Highway 118."
布蘭登那個該死的笨蛋
Robert Brenton, that dumb fuck!
那笨蛋蠢得要命，活該要死
That stupid shit was so dumb,he deserved to die!
王八羔子!
That asshole!
蒂米，4號房在搞什麼鬼，整天亮著燈？
Timmy, what's going on in No. 4, where them lights are always on?
他們在拍色情片，德州風味!
Them are making a pornographic movie, Texas style!
怎麼，想客串一下？
You wanna join in?
在金槍魚鎮混，就得多點幽默感
To survive in Big Tuna, you need an active sense of humor!
這位是波斯•史布，我們叫他"老史"
This is Bosis Spool. We call him "DO Spool".
他是位火箭科學家!
The man is a rocket scientist!
我的狗在叫
My dog barks some.
你在腦子裡想像它是什麼樣的
Mentally, you picture my dog,
可是，我還沒告訴你
but, I have not told you
它是什麼種的
the type of dog which I have.
也許你會想到
Perhaps you might even picture Toto
《綠野仙蹤》裡那隻狗托托
from the "Wizard of Oz".
但是我可以告訴你們，我的狗一直跟我在一起
But I can tell you my dog is always with me.
嗨，伙計們好!
Hey everybody!
波比! 嗨，賽勒，露拉
Bobby! Hey, Sailor, Lula,
我跟你們說的就是他! 波比，這是賽勒和露拉
This is the man himself! Bobby, this is Sailor and Lula,
兩位剛從外地來
the 2 most recent strandees,
手頭也不怎麼寬裕
of the economic variety.
波比•佩魯，我喜歡這地方
Bobby Peru. Like the country.
波比幾天前纔到這兒
Bobby just rolled into town a few days ago.
現在再也沒有出現像波比這麼叫人興奮的人物了
Yeah, Bobby is the most exciting item
嘿，自1986年那場
to hit Big Tuna since the '86 cyclone
掀掉中學屋頂的龍卷風以後
sheared the roof off the high school.
你是德州人嗎，佩魯先生？
You from Texas, Mr. Peru?
我四海為家
I'm from all over.
你在海軍陸戰隊待過
You were in the Marines.
四年
Four years.
- 波比之前在朝阪待過 - 朝阪是什麼？
Bobby was at Cao Ben. - What's Cao Ben?
- 你多大了？  - 20
How old are you? - Twenty.
許多老弱婦幼都死在朝阪
A lot of women and kids and old people died at Cao Ben.
當時是在一艘船上，兄弟
You was on a ship, partner.
當你在越南北部東京灣裡漂浮時
Pretty hard to make contact with the people,
很難和人有接觸
when you're out floating in the Golf of Tonkin.
來吧，波比，再來一杯催情劑
Come on Bobby, have another glass of Jack.
我倒不介意喝一杯
Don't mind if I fuckin' do.
提到做那事
Speakin' of Jack ...
有首歌唱得好: 對面的女孩躺下來，躺下來
One-eyed Jack's yearning to go peeping in a seafood store ...
好了
Alright.
很高興認識你們
Nice meetin' you.
- 祝你們平安，伙計們 - 再見，波比
Adios, boys! - See ya, Bobby!
波比就喜歡這個
Bobby's got a way ...
沒法讓他腦子不想那玩意兒
Can't shake that institution out of him.
寶貝，我還是覺得不大舒服，我去睡了
Baby, I still ain't feelin' so well. I'm goin' to bed.
- 你也來嗎？      - 好的，我跟你回去
Will you come with me? - Yeah, I'll come along.
就這樣
Well ...
- 晚安! - 晚安!
Good night! - Good night!
老天，剛纔是怎麼回事？
Lordy, what was that about?
不清楚
I don't know ...
媽的，那股酸味還沒散
Man, that barf smell don't fade fast.
我能為你做些什麼？
Is there anything I can do for you?
我想沒有，小賽
I don't think so, Sail'.
我隻想躺下
I just need to lie down.
知道嗎？
You know what?
我明白你不大喜歡這裡
I know you ain't too pleased being here.
不是這樣
It's not that.
我要把它寫下來
I'm gonna write it down,
我沒法說出口
because I can't say it.
沒法說出口？
You can't say it?
對，我說不了
I can't say this, not out loud.
"我懷孕了"
I'M PREGNANT.
老天!
Oh God!
對我來說沒問題，親愛的
It's okay by me, Peanut.
不是針對你
Well, nothing personal ...
但我不敢肯定，是不是對我也沒問題
But I ain't so sure it's okay by me.
真的，小賽，我不是說你有什麼不好
Really, Sail', it's nothing against you, baby.
我愛你啊
I love you.
我也愛你
I love you too.
我知道
I know.
隻是自從我們在黃磚路拋錨後
I'm just sort of uncomfortable about how things are going,
發生的一切讓我難受
since we broke down along that Yellow Brick Road,
而懷孕也沒法給我安慰
and this doesn't soothe me.
親愛的，我保證不會讓事情變得更糟
Honey, I promise I ain't gonna let things get no worse.
我發誓
Not in a million years.
嗨，美人兒，賽勒在嗎？
Hey, pretty woman. Is Sailor here?
- 不，他在給我們的車換機油 - 我尿急
No, he's changing oil out in our car. - I gotta take a piss, bad,
能借你的頭用一下嗎？
can I use your head?
啊  我想可以
Oh ... yeah, I guess.
我不是真的指你的頭  我當然不會尿在你頭上
I don't mean your head head ... I'm not goin' to piss on your hair,
隻是借一下廁所
just gonna piss in the toilet.
仔細聽好，波比•佩魯的泉水叮咚響
Ya'll take a listen, you'll hear a deep sound comin' from Bobby Peru!
這屋子有股嘔吐後的味道
There's a smell in this room of puke.
是你吐的？
Have you been puking?
你病了？
Are you sick?
- 懷孕了？    - 廁所借完了，你可以走了
Pregnant?   - You used the toilet, now go!
我做什麼與你無關
It ain't none of your business what I do around here!
我就喜歡有你這樣一對寶貝的女人
I sure do like a woman with nice tits like yours,
說話兇巴巴，干起事來像兔子
who talks tough and looks like she can fuck like a bunny.
你在床上是這樣嗎？
Can you fuck like that?
干起來像兔子？
You like it like a bunny?
要是這樣，小妞，我會叫你更爽
'Cause if you do, baby, I'll fuck you good,
像大野兔一樣，在洞裡亂跳
like a big old jack-rabbit, jump all around that hole!
波比的功夫是一流的
Bobby Peru don't come up for air!
滾出去!
Get out!
我讓你害怕了？
Am I scarin' you?
你下面濕了？
Is your pussy wet?
濕了沒有？
Is it wet?
噢，你跳得這麼慢
Oh, don't jump back so slow.
我還以為你是隻兔子，兔子跳得很快
I thought you was a bunny! Bunnies jump fast.
但你這麼慢
You jump back slow.
是某種暗示，對嗎？
Means something, don't it?
你在對我暗示
Means something to me.
你想要波比
Means you want Bobby Peru.
你要波比把你干得天昏地暗，小妞
You want Bobby Peru to fuck you hard, baby,
像開聖誕禮物一樣把你弄開
to open you like a Christmas present!
你要我做嗎？ 隻需回答"要"或者"不要"
You want me to do it? Just a simple "yes" or "no".
好好享受一下我和你的第一次親密接觸
Just feel me breathin' on ya.
- 你就知道我在床上很行  - 滾出去
And you know I mean business when it comes to fuckin' ! - Out!
波比會抓住你
Bobby Peru will grab ya ...
把你緊緊抱住
hold ya tight ...
好好嘗嘗你裡面的味道
feel everythin' in ya.
閉嘴
Be quiet!
說"操我"
Say "Fuck me".
- 我就走     - 沒門，快給我滾!
Then I'll leave.  - No way. Get out!
說! 我會把你的心挖出來的，小妞
Say it! I'll tear your fuckin' heart out, girl!
說"操我"
Say "Fuck me".
快說
Say "Fuck me"!
然後我就走，說"操我"
Then I'll go. Say "Fuck me"!
小聲地，說出來!
Whisper it. Say it!
說，說!
Say it. Say it!
說"操我"
Say "Fuck me".
小聲說"操我"
Whisper it. "Fuck me".
"操我"，說啊
"Fuck me". Say "Fuck me".
改天吧，寶貝，今天我還有事
Some day honey, I will! But I gotta get goin' !
拜托別哭了
Sing! Don't cry ...
嗨，波比
Hi Bobby!
- 要幫忙嗎？     - 謝謝，快做完了
You need a hand?  - Thanks, but I'm about done.
去喝杯啤酒如何？
How about a beer?
啤酒
A beer ...
那好
Well, ...
好吧，波比，我去
Yeah, Bobby, that'd be fine.
你那位俊俏的小姑娘今天在哪？
Where is your pretty little lady today?
在房間裡休息，最近身體不大舒服
She's up in our room, restin'. Hasn't been feelin' well lately.
真遺憾
Sorry to hear it.
我去羅波鎮探過底了
I've been studying a situation over in Lobo.
要兩個人纔能干成
Take two men to handle it.
干什麼？
What's that?
一家飼料店，保險箱裡藏著五千美金
A feed store, keeps up to 5 K in their safe.
我要個醒目的小伙子斷後，五五分帳
Need me a good boy for backup. Even split.
怎麼樣？
Interested?
不，朋友
No, man.
我想不行
I don't think so.
輕而易舉就能搞定的，賽勒
It'll be easy, Sailor.
我會讓兩個職員乖乖打開保險箱，你看好門
Two employees. I take 'em in back to open the safe. You cover the door.
你不是忙活著想在金槍魚鎮
You ain't plannin' on raisin'
成家立業嗎？
a family in the Big Tuna, are you?
等一等
Wait a minute ...
你在說什麼成家立業？
What'd you mean by family?
我隻是說
Well, I mean ...
和露拉
with Lula ...
小兩口過得有個家的樣子，沒別的意思
being in a family way and all.
露拉告訴你她懷孕了嗎？
Did Lula tell you she was pregnant?
手裡攥著幾千塊,你們就不用過苦日子
Couple of grand or two sure would help you two out.
可以離開這鬼地方，到墨西哥或者其他什麼地方，隻要有錢
Get you out West, to Mexico, or anywhere with a few dollars to spare.
我都替你們經算好了，賽勒
I've got it figured out good.
你什麼時候跟露拉說過話？
When did you talk to Lula?
今天下午
I talked to her this afternoon,
你不在的時候
when you was out.
她真的親口跟你說她懷孕了？
Did she really say she was pregnant?
我瞎猜罷了，就這麼回事
I just took a guess, that's all.
你到底參不參加？
You in or out on this deal?
我他媽的還不清楚，波比
I ain't fucking sure, Bobby.
別考慮太久
Don't take too long to think about it.
喝夠了？
Had enough?
夠了!
Have now!
跟我出去一下，有好東西給你瞧
Let's go outside. I have something to show you.
這是一把鋸短的
Right here is a double-barreled, sawed-off
雙管獵槍
Ithica shotgun.
旁邊那把
Next to it;
是槍管4汲イ牡閎八手槍
a Smith & Wesson .38 handgun with a 4-inch barrel.
有了這些家伙
Those'll do her,
那五千塊錢就能輕松入袋
really loosen up that 5 grand.
你和小姑娘拿一半
Two and a half for you and the little lady.
你身上還剩多少？
How much money you got left?
40塊
Forty bucks ...
兄弟，這筆錢轉眼就能賺到
This is easy money, partner.
也不會讓任何人受傷
Ain't nobody gonna get hurt.
這麼個大好機會，你不會讓它白白溜走
And I don't think you can afford to pass it up ...
明早10點，我的車在旅館後面等你
I'll bring the Eldorado to the back of the motel at 10 AM.
肯定能叫你和小姑娘過上舒服的小日子
Really could set you and that little lady up good.
是啊，我想是可以
Yeah, I guess so.
這筆錢
That kinda money
可以讓我們在黃磚路上走下去
will get us a long way down that Yellow Brick Road.
但是真該死，你得保證到時可別出什麼差池
But damn it, this better go real smooth, you understand me?
簡直就像囊中探物一樣保險
Like taking candy from a baby.
賽勒來了
Here comes Sailor.
你喝酒了？
You've been drinkin', huh?
幾杯啤酒而已
A few beers is all.
感覺好點沒？
Feelin' any better?
還不清楚
Can't tell yet.
還是滿屋子那股味道
That smell's still filling this room good.
你剛纔說你去哪兒了？
So where d'you say you was?
和波比出去了
I went with Bobby.
小賽
Sail'?
我們離開這裡吧
Let's leave here.
我們會的，心肝
We are, Peanut.
很快
Real soon.
你和波比那家伙在一起混？
You up to somethin' with Bobby Peru?
我能混什麼？
What could I be up to?
那個波比是人面獸心，小賽
That Bobby Peru is a black angel, Sail'.
要是你跟他鬼混，你要後悔的
You hook up with him and you'll regret it ...
後悔一輩子
If you live to.
多謝你的提醒，親愛的
Thanks, darling.
我知道你為我著想
I know you got my interests in mind,
我非常感激
and I appreciate it sincerely.
我愛你，但是我得睡了
I love you, but I got to get some sleep now.
這個世界內心狂野，頭腦發熱
This whole world is wild at heart ... and weird on top.
我盼著你能對我唱"柔情似水"
I wish you'd sing me "Love me tender".
我真希望我們是在那彩虹之上
Oh, I wish I was somewhere over that rainbow.
一切全是狗屁!
It's just shit!
狗屁! 狗屁! 狗屁!
Shit, shit, shit!
這是全家福？
The whole gang, huh?
沒錯
Yes.
知道嗎，你真人看起來要漂亮得多
You know, you look a whole lot better in the flesh.
一切都按計劃進行
The cobra is waitin' to strike, Chica.
你認識那個叫賽勒的家伙？
You know that guy, Sailor?
前幾天他來過這兒
He came by the other afternoon.
- 想打聽是不是有人想殺他 - 真的？
He wanted to know if there was a contract on him. - No shit?
- 你認識他？ - 以前認識.
You know him? - I used to.
- 你怎麼回答？. - 當然是"沒有"
What did you say? - "No", of course.
沒錯
That's right.
不過他很快就會倒大霉
He could have a bad accident, though.
在一宗搶劫之前
Before,
或是之中，要不就是之後
during or after a hold-up.
我到底在這兒做什麼？
What am I doing here?
賽勒，你到底在這兒做什麼？
Sailor, what are you doing here?
我不能干
I can't do this.
坐到後面去
Climb in back!
她在這裡干什麼？
What the hell's she doin' here?
她是我女人，給我們開車，你不喜歡？
She's my girl. She's drivin'. That bother you?
快上車
Jump in!
你欠我一人情
You owe me one.
來吧，大膽先生
Come on, Mr. Big Round Balls,
我們去賺點容易到手的錢
let's go and make us some easy money.
俗話說得好: 星期五都是黑色的
They say the eagle flies on Friday.
把絲襪戴上
Get that mask on!
別熄火，我們去去就來
Keep it revvin', Chiquita. We'll be right back!
我們說好不傷人，別忘了
Nobody's gonna get hurt. Remember that!
好的，兄弟
Right, partner!
行了，伙計們
Okay, boys!
到後面去，兩個都到後面去
Get in the back! Get into the back! Now! Both of you!
如果有人進來，把他們也推過來，手腳要利索
If anyone comes in, herd 'em back here quick.
好的，別把事情搞糟就行
Alright, let's make this nice and easy!
你在等人嗎？
You waitin' for somebody?
我丈夫
My husband.
他在飼料店
He's in the feed store.
小心煙頭燒到手，女士
Well, watch that cigarette, ma'am. It's about to burn down to your fingers.
謝謝，長官
Thank you, officer.
以前沒見過你，你是本地人？
I haven't seen you before. Are you from Lobo?
不是
No.
過來
Over here!
金槍魚鎮上的？
Big Tuna, huh?
- 開車路不近啊，對不對？  - 對
That's quite a drive, isn't it?  - Yes.
咱們走吧!
Let's go!
笑一笑
Say "Cheese".
別動
Stay put!
別衝動，朋友
Cool it, man!
下一個就是你了，混蛋
You're next, fucker!
那些都是笨蛋
Those are dummies, dummy!
你有種就過來，神槍手
Step up here, hotshot!
我會叫你滿地找你那口爛牙
I'll slap that smile right off your face!
站住，你們這班王八蛋
Stop, you sons of bitches!
警察! 站住，要不我開槍了
This is the police! Hold it or I'll shoot!
噢，老天
Oh, for Christ's sakes!
那個王八蛋
That poor bastard.
把手放到頭上，牛仔
Hands behind your head, cowboy!
露拉，我這次真的叫你失望了
Lula, I really let you down this time.
我的心肝
Peanut!
快幫我找那該死的雜碎
Look for the damned thing!
會找到的，醫生會給你縫上
We'll find it, they sew them things back on.
將來又可完好如初
Works good as new.
找不到，那該死的雜碎到底在哪？
I can't find it. Where is the damned thing?
一定在這附近
It's gotta be here somewhere.
打擾一下，我找770378號
Pardon me. I'm lookin' for 770378.
小賽，寶貝
Sailor, baby!
我的天! 我的天!
Oh my God! Oh my God!
心肝寶貝，終於找到你了
My baby, sweetest one. Oh, sweetheart.
媽媽這就帶你回家
Mama's gonna take you home. We're gonna go home.
桑托斯會幫我們的忙
Santos is gonna help us.
搭我們到聖安東尼奧機場
He's gonna take us to the airport in San Antonio.
- 沒事了，寶貝 - 不     - 沒事了
It's OK, baby. - No ... - Yes.
來吧，我們得走了
Come! We're gonna go.
- 沒事了 - 媽媽   - 干嘛？.
It's OK. - Mama! - Yes?
賽勒出事了，我不能就這樣撇下他
Sailor's in deep trouble here. I can't just leave him.
怎麼不能？
Oh yes, you can!
你當然可以
Yes, you can!
你媽媽真的很擔心你
Your mama was real worried about you, honey.
我也是
Me too.
不介意擁抱一下你的老朋友桑托斯吧
Can you give your old friend Santos a hug?
最親愛的賽勒
Dearest Sailor,
我想讓你知道的第一件事， 是我留住了孩子
First thing you'll want to know is; I'm keeping the baby.
媽媽開始反對，現在估計也是
Mama wasn't for it at first, but I think now she is.
我叫他佩思，不管是男孩還是女孩
I'm gonna name it Pace, no matter if it's a boy or a girl.
有點難以想像，你出來時佩思已經六歲了
It's kinda hard to believe that Pace will be six when you get out.
我們的孩子!
Our child!
我愛你，賽勒
I love you, Sailor.
我想給跟你跳舞說話
I miss dancing and talking,
特別是做那件事!
and especially the other!
5年10個月零21天後
5 YEARS, 10 MONTHS, 21 DAYS LATER
賽勒的火車  什麼時候  到？
When ... does ... Sailor's train get in?
六點
Six.
要是我叫你不要去
If I asked you not to go ...
沒用的
It wouldn't make any difference.
孩子，要是我叫你不要去會怎麼樣？
Girl, what if I told you not to go?
媽媽，如果你想破壞我們的幸福
Mama, if you get in the way of our happiness,
我會把你撕成肉片的!
I'll fucking pull your arms out by the roots!
不許去!
No!
媽媽，你差點跟人撞車呢
Mama, you almost crashed us!
是車禍，寶貝
Oh, an accident, baby!
喔，我的天啊
Oh no, oh man!
去年這種爛事也撞到我頭上
Same fuckin' thing happened to me last year!
你一定是我兒子
You must be my son.
跟你爸爸握握手，兒子
Shake hands with your daddy, Pace.
見到你真榮幸，小伙子，我讀了不少你的事
It's a pleasure to meet you, Pace. I read a lot about you.
餓了嗎？
Are you hungry?
前面帶路
Lead the way.
不!
No!
怎麼了，媽媽？
What's wrong, Mama?
別擔心，兒子，在這兒待著
Don't worry, son. Just stay here.
對不起，賽勒，我忍不住
I'm sorry, Sailor, I just can't help it.
再等一會，我會沒事的
Just give me one little minute, then I'll quit.
孩子嚇到了，露拉，這樣不好
The boy's frightened, Lula. This ain't no good.
真的，賽勒，我會沒事的
Really, Sailor, I'll be okay.
天意弄人，寶貝
It's a mistake, honey.
你們倆走吧，我回火車站
You two go on. I'll walk back to the depot.
你胡說些什麼？車裡是你親生兒子
What are you talking about? That's your son in there!
他不認識我，露拉
He never knew me, Lula.
所以也應很容易忘掉我
So there's not much for him to forget.
而且六年不見，分開對我們也很容易
And 6 years apart makes it almost simple for us too.
你怎麼能說這種話，賽勒？
How can you say that, Sailor?
這纔合情理
It's what makes sense.
求你別這麼做，賽勒
Please don't do this, Sailor!
如果你有什麼不順心的事
If ever something
doesn't feel right to you,
想想牛仔潘喬對四酷小子說的話
remember what Pancho said to the Cisco Kid;
"在山窮水盡之前，瀟灑走一回"
"Let's win, before we're dancing at the end of a rope, without music."
沒有我，你過得很好
You've been fine without me.
沒必要讓日子變得難過
No need to make life tougher than it has to be.
賽勒，回來
Sailor, come back!
你們這班基佬想干嘛？
What do you faggots want?
那個好女巫
The Good Witch ...
露拉愛你
Lula loves you.
但我是殺人犯兼強盜
But I'm a robberand a man slaughterer.
而且沒有受過多少家庭教育
And I haven't had any parental guidance.
這些她都不在乎
She's forgiven you all that.
你愛她
You love her.
別擔心，賽勒
Don't be afraid, Sailor.
但是我心狂野
But I'm wild at heart.
如果你真是這樣
If you are truly wild at heart,
那你就會為你的夢想而奮鬥
you'll fight for your dreams.
別逃避愛情，賽勒
Don't turn away from love, Sailor.
別逃避愛情
Don't turn away from love.
嘗夠滋味沒，混蛋？
Had enough, asshole?
是的，夠了
Yes I have.
我向你們道歉
And I want to apologize to you gentlemen
不該叫你們同性戀
for referring to you as homosexuals.
我還想向你們道謝
I also want to thank you fellows.
你們教會我人生重要一課
You've taught me a valuable lesson in life.
我剛遇見那個好女巫
I just met the Good Witch.
-=劇終=-